ZACH MASON

Zzacharycmason@gmail.com **②** zaturnvalley.github.io/Portfolio **↓** 425.458.8992 **۞** zaturnvalley

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack, front-end leaning web developer with a Masters in Teaching. I am experienced with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js), SQL, Ruby on Rails, Marketo, and more. When I'm not coding, I'm producing music, traveling, and spending time with my dog and wife.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Python, C#

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES:

AngularJS, Rails, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, ReactJS, MeteorJS DATABASES: SQL, MongoDB OTHER SKILLS: Research,

Collaboration, Leadership, Conflict Resolution, Teaching

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive 2016

 Building projects utilizing Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Angular.js, SQL, Ruby on Rails.

Seattle University

Masters in Teaching 2013

• Endorsements: History & Social Studies.

Pepperdine University B.A. History 2008

• Studied abroad in Heidelberg, Germany (2005 - 2006)

PROJECTS

Consignment Shop App

Aug 2017

Sep 2016

A C# App that can be used by consignment shops to run their business. Includes list of vendor, items, commission,

Marvel Hero Explorer

Mar 2017 - Apr 2017

A Windows 10 App Marvel Hero App using C#, XAML, and the Marvel Hero API

Portfolio

My personal portfolio. Contains links to all projects, personal bio, resume, and contact. Link:

https://zaturnvalley.github.io/Portfolio/

Oct 2016

A MEAN stack app that helps users make decisions based on averaged data. Uses Chart, js for visualizations, MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, and Node.js. Link: http://indecisivelife.herokuapp.com/

Aug 2016

A full stack app that allows you to search a video game API and rate / review games. Used HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, SQL, Sequelize, Express, AJAX, Bcrypt, EJS & EJS Layouts, Passport. Link: http://gameranker.herokuapp.com/

Sep 2016 Chat Emoji

A full-stack Ruby on Rails web socket app designed by a team of 4 collaboratively. The app's focus centered around helping users to find and live chat with like-minded patrons. Technologies Used: Ruby on Rails + Active Record, Web Socket / Action Cable, User Authentication, HTML / CSS, Postgres, CoffeeScript, Wireframes, Emoji Picker Gem, and Bcrypt.

Resume Wordifier

A sprint development fullstack collaborative app completed during a 24 hour hackathon. Wordifier takes any job description and builds a cloud map of the main keywords on the page. Technologies used: MongoDb, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js, Mongoose, JWT.

Game of War + 52 Card Pick Up

Aug 2016

Utilized HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery to create a game of war and 52 card pick up simulation. Link: https://zaturnvalley.github.io/GameOfWar/

EMPLOYMENT

Catalysis, Jr. Front End Developer, Seattle, WA

Jan 2017 - Current, Jan 2017 - Current

Developing Microsoft emails and landing webpages using ExactTarget, Marketo and technologies such as HTML, CSS, AmpScript, and JavaScript. Deploying collaborative quick iterations of builds involving: QAing, unit testing, and debugging in order to deliver highly responsive marketing promotions and newsletters.

General Assembly Immersive, Web Developer, Seattle, WA

Jul 2016 - Oct 2016

• 12 week immersive course with 480 hours of instruction, 5 sprint development projects in an agile environment. Utilized HTML, CSS, Javascript, MEAN stack (MongoDB, Express, Angular.js, Node.js), SQL, Ruby on Rails.

Kent School District, Social Studies Teacher, Kent, WA

Aug 2015 - Jun 2016

- Taught 9th grade Contemporary World History & 11th grade US History
- Cycle of Inquiry Growth Goal met by 90% of students; writing with evidence

• Collaborated with PLC to design unit lesson plans and assessments; analyzed data.

Bellevue School District, Substitute Teacher, Bellevue, WA • Instructed 4-12th grade History, English, Humanities, Government, & Economics.

Huntington Learning Center, Tutor, Bothell, WA

Aug 2013 - Jun 2015 Feb 2011 - Dec 2011

• Taught K-12th grade students. Trained new tutors and monitored student progress.

EFL Institute, English Teacher, Daegu, South Korea

Jul 2009 - Jul 2010

• Managed and taught K-8th grade Korean students in reading, writing, & English.